

# Khrystyna Fedyuk

Lisbon, Portugal

**(**+351) 910728342

★ kfedyuk.geral@gmail.com

in khrystyna-fedyuk

khrystynafedyuk.me

kfedyuk

## **Profile**

I'm from Loulé (in Algarve) and moved to Lisbon 5 years ago to study the course I'm finishing now. This experience has thrown a huge amount of obstacles and responsibilities at me through the years, allowing me to grow a whole lot.

I consider myself a persistent and curious person, I like challenges where I can grow and learn new things. Currently, one of my main interests is distributed computing, which is the field of my master's thesis on the theme "Sheik: Dynamic location and binding of microservices for cloud/edge settings".

## **Education**

2014 – 2020 Faculdade de Ciências e Tecnologia da Universidade Nova de Lisboa,

Integrated M.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

• Currently working on my thesis to end the course. My average grade is 15.

Sep 2017 - Jan 2018

**Université Grenoble Alpes,** M.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

• A semester in Grenoble, France by the Erasmus program, where I took the Programming language and compiler design course.

Sep 2017 – Jan 2018

National School of Computer Science and Applied Mathematics of Grenoble,

M.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering

• A semester in Grenoble, France by the Erasmus program where I took the Human Computer Interaction and Parallel Systems courses.

# **Professional Experience**

May 2019 - Oct 2019

## LightKone - Lightweight Computation for Networks at the Edge,

Research Grant

Worked with the Computer Systems Groups of NOVA LINCS, during development of my master's thesis, to design an architecture, potentially based on microservice architectures, that will manage the execution of distributed applications across the cloud-edge spectrum. I focused on developing and testing a Java based discovery service for microservices for cloud/edge settings.

Mar 2019 – Jul 2019

**NOVA FCT,** *Teaching Assistant* 

Selected to support the course Algorithms and Data Structures at NOVA FCT (taught in C), being responsible for teaching a class of Electrical Engineering BSc students during the Spring semester.

Jul 2018 - Aug 2018

**NetCAOS**, **Lda**, *Internship* 

Worked in a team in web development with VB.NET - ASP.NET MVC and SQL Server to test and extend a backoffice management website with an automatic billing system, integrated with API Mandrill, IfThenPay and WeoInvoice.

## Skills

#### **Programming Languages**

Java (Maven, Gradle), C, C++, C#, Python, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS

#### **Other Tools**

Git, Postman, Tomcat, Google App Engine, Amazon EC2, MongoDB, levelDB, Google Cloud Data Store, SQL Server, MySQL

## **Frameworks and Libraries**

Spring, Jersey, React (Gatsby), Akka

## **Spoken Languages**

Portuguese, English, French, Russian, Ukrainian

# **Other Activities**

#### 2020

# Personal Website, Project

My personal website that I developed with Gatsby and React as I didn't like the idea of using a template and wanted to make it more personal.

#### Apr 2018 - 2019

# **ExpoFCT, Volunteer**

ExpoFCT is an annual event where each department shows its educational offer to pre-university (or younger) students through different workshops and activities.

- 2019 Helped my department in the preparations for ExpoFCT and was part of a team responsible to introduce and guide the NanoRobots activity, where students learned basic programming concepts in an interactive and simple way with the help of Ozobots.
- 2018 Invited to present my project "Almada Consigo" in the "Innovation Projects" section, where students showcase interesting projects that they developed.

#### 2017

## Almada Consigo, Project

Project developed as part of the Engineering Project course where I developed, in a team of 5 people, an Angular frontend application with Java backend, supported by Google App Engine, along with an Android mobile application. The application is a service that allows you to post occurrences on the public road, such as potholes, and follow the resolution process, as well as share it and obtain feedback from the community.